A Guide to the Annie Louise Cole Tansill Letters, 1874-1883
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Annie Louise Cole Tansill Letters, 1874-1883
The Library of Virginia
38438
55 pages
Annie Louise Cole Tansill
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 9 February 2000, from Colonial S. C. S., East Northport, New York.
Biographical Information
Annie Cole Tansill was born in Prince William County, Virginia, on 20 October 1850. She was the daughter of Horace and Martha Ann Cole. On 6 February 1868, she married Wallace Norman Tansill (1845-1926), and they had at least 6 children. The Tansills first lived in Prince William County where he was a jailer, then they moved to Fredericksburg, Virginia, where he was employed as a postman. Annie Tansill died in Fredericksburg 11 July 1943, and was buried in the Tansill family plot in the city cemetery.
Scope and Content
Letters, 1874-1883, to Annie Louise Cole Tansill (1850-1943) of Prince William County and Fredericksburg, Virginia, consisting of letters from her husband Wallace N. Tansill (1845-1926), sister Virginia Leary (1841-1909), her niece Lulu Leary (b. ca. 1862), and her friends Mollie and Lewellen Lynn, all containing family and personal news from Prince William County; Hampshire County, West Virginia; and Washington D.C.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Annie Louise Cole Tansill letters, 1865-1868 (LVA accessions 37057, 37552; both accessions filed together).
Contents List
- Letter, 8 August 1874, from Mollie in Hampshire County, West Virginia, sending news about family and friends, informing Annie that she's teaching Sunday school, discussing the use of jellies, and encouraging Annie to move to Hampshire County.
- Letter, 24 September 1874, from Lewellen Lynn of Washington D.C. apologizing for not writing sooner, sending family news, and asking Annie to write.
- Letter, 1 November 1874, from Mollie sending personal and family news, letter incomplete.
- Letter, 11 June 1876, from (Mary) Virginia Leary, her sister, expressing concern over the health of one of Annie's children, regretting having to keep her children out of school to do work at home, and informing Annie that they are living comfortably.
- Letter, 30 July 1876, from Virginia Leary describing a rain storm that ended a drought, discussing the difficulties lack of rain had on growing crops, and sending personal news
- Letter, 20 August 1876, from Virginia Leary sending personal news and asking about family and friends.
- Letter, 13 January 1877, from Lulu Leary and Virginia Leary providing family news and encouraging Annie to come visit.
- Letter, 29 July 1877, from Virginia Leary concerning her family, wishing for better fruit, and the "Nelson Mill Scandal."
- Letter, 25 January 1878, from Virginia Leary providing family news.
- Letter, 11 June 1878, from Lewellen Lynn sending news and asking Annie for any.
- Letter, 18 July 1880, from her husband Wallace N. Tansill containing personal news.
- Letter, 21 September 1880, from (Mary) Lulu Leary concerning the birth of Viola Pearl Leary, her brother's support for the candidacy of Winfield Hancock for president, a carnival show she attended, and other family news.
- Letter, 29 May 1881, from Virginia Leary providing news about her family and local events, discussing planting, and complaining about her husband.
- Letter, 9 September 1883, from Lulu Leary containing family and personal news, letter is incomplete.
- Letter, 25 October 1883, from Lulu Leary informing Annie that her father added teaching to his medical profession, sending family and personal news, and wishing to visit
- Letter, 31 March no year, from "A" informing Annie that she plans to marry.